

<string-array name="chapter_1">
	<item>Location of the Arabs</item> 
	<item>Arab Tribes</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_1_content">
	<item>
		Beyond a shadow of doubt, the biography of Prophet Muhammad (Peace be upon him) manifestedly
		represents an exhaustive embodiment of the sublime Divine Message that he communicated in order
		to deliver the human race from the swamp of darkness and polytheism to the paradise of light and
		monotheism. An image, authentic as well as comprehensive, of this Message is therefore only
		attainable through careful study and profound analysis of both backgrounds and issues of such a
		biography. In view of this, a whole chapter is here introduced about the nature and development of
		Arab tribes prior to Islam as well as the circumstantial environment that enwrapped the Prophet’s
		mission. 
	</item>
	<item>
		Linguistically, the word “Arab” means deserts and waste barren land well-nigh waterless and
		treeless. Ever since the dawn of history, the Arabian Peninsula and its people have been called as
		such.
		The Arabian Peninsula is enclosed in the west by the Red Sea and Sinai, in the east by the Arabian
		Gulf, in the south by the Arabian Sea, which is an extension of the Indian Ocean, and in the north
		by old Syria and part of Iraq. The area is estimated between a million and a million and a quarter
		square miles.
		Thanks to its geographical position, the peninsula has always maintained great importance..
		Considering its internal setting, it is mostly deserts and sandy places, which has rendered it
		inaccessible to foreigners and invaders, and allowed its people complete liberty and independence
		through the ages, despite the presence of two neighbouring great empires.
		Its external setting, on the other hand, caused it to be the centre of the old world and provided it
		with sea and land links with most nations at the time. Thanks to this strategic position the Arabian
		Peninsula had become the centre for trade, culture, religion and art. 
	</item>
	<item>
		Arab kinfolks have been divided according to lineage into three groups:
		Perishing Arabs: The ancient Arabs, of whose history little is known, and of whom were ‘Ad,
		Thamûd, Tasam, Jadis, Emlaq, and others.
		Pure Arabs: Who originated from the progeny of Ya‘rub bin Yashjub bin Qahtan. They were also
		called Qahtanian Arabs.
		Arabized Arabs: Who originated from the progeny of Ishmael. They were also called ‘Adnanian
		Arabs.
		The pure Arabs – the people of Qahtan – originally lived in Yemen and comprised many tribes, two
		of which were very famous:
		1. Himyar: The most famous of whose septs were Zaid Al-Jamhur, Quda‘a and Sakasic.
		2. Kahlan: The most famous of whose septs were Hamdan, Anmar, Tai’, Mudhhij, Kinda,
		Lakhm, Judham, Azd, Aws, Khazraj and the descendants of Jafna — the kings of old Syria.
		Kahlan septs emigrated from Yemen to dwell in the different parts of the Arabian Peninsula prior to
		the Great Flood (Sail Al-‘Arim of Ma’rib Dam), due to the failure of trade under the Roman pressure
		and domain on both sea and land trade routes following Roman occupation of Egypt and Syria.
		Naturally enough, the competition between Kahlan and Himyar led to the evacuation of the first and
		the settlement of the second in Yemen.
		THE EMIGRATING SEPTS OF KAHLAN CAN BE INTO FOUR GROUPS:
		1. Azd: Who, under the leadership of ‘Imran bin ‘Amr Muzaiqbâ’, wandered in Yemen, sent
		pioneers and finally headed northwards. Details of their emigration can be summed up as
		follows: 
		2. Tha‘labah bin ‘Amr left his tribe Al-Azd for Hijaz and dwelt between Tha‘labiyah and Dhi Qar.
		When he gained strength, he headed for Madinah where he stayed. Of his seed are Aws and
		Khazraj, sons of Haritha bin Tha‘labah.
		Haritha bin ‘Amr, known as Khuza‘a, wandered with his folks in Hijaz until they came to Mar
		Az-Zahran. Later, they conquered the Haram, and settled in Makkah after having driven
		away its people, the tribe of Jurhum.
		‘Imran bin ‘Amr and his folks went to ‘Oman where they established the tribe of Azd whose
		children inhabited Tihama and were known as Azd-of-Shanu’a.
		Jafna bin ‘Amr and his family, headed for Syria where he settled and initiated the kingdom
		of Ghassan who was so named after a spring of water, in Hijaz, where they s topped on their
		way to Syria.
		2. Lakhm and Judham: Of whom was Nasr bin Rabi‘a, father of Manadhira, Kings of Heerah.
		3. Banu Tai’: Who also emigrated northwards to settle by the so- called Aja and Salma
		Mountains which were consequently named as Tai’ Mountains.
		4. Kinda: Who dwelt in Bahrain but were expelled to Hadramout and Najd where they instituted
		a powerful government but not for long , for the whole tribe soon faded away.
		• Another tribe of Himyar, known as Quda‘a, also left Yemen and dwelt in Samawa semidesert
		on the borders of Iraq.
		The Arabized Arabs go back in ancestry to their great grandfather Abraham (Peace be upon him)
		from a town called “Ar” near Kufa on the west bank of the Euphrates in Iraq. Excavations brought to
		light great details of the town, Abraham’s family, and the prevalent religions and social
		circumstances.
		It is known that Abrahaml (Peace be upon him) eft Ar for Harran and then for Palestine, which he
		made headquarters for his Message. He wandered all over the area. When he went to E gypt, the
		Pharaoh tried to do evil to his wife Sarah, but Allâh saved her and the Pharaoh’s wicked scheme
		recoiled on him. He thus came to realize her strong attachment to Allâh, and, in acknowledgment of
		her grace, the Pharaoh rendered his daughter Hagar at Sarah’s service, but Sarah gave Hagar to
		Abraham as a wife.
		Abraham returned to Palestine where Hagar gave birth to Ishmael. Sarah became so jealous of
		Hagar that she forced Abraham to send Hagar and her baby away to a plantless valley on a small
		hill in Hijaz, by the Sacred House, exposed to the wearing of floods coming right and left. He chose
		for them a place under a lofty tree above Zamzam near the upper side of the Mosque in Makkah
		where neither people nor water was available, and went back to Palestine leaving with his wife and
		baby a leather case with some dates and a pot of water. Not before long, they ran out of both food
		and water, but thanks to Allâh’s favour water gushed forth to sustain them for sometime. The whole
		story of Zamzam spring is already known to everybody.
		Another Yemeni tribe – Jurhum the Second – came and lived in Makkah upon Hagar’s permission,
		after being said to have lived in the valleys around Makkah. It is mentioned in the Sahih Al-Bukhari
		that this tribe came to Makkah before Ishmael was a young man while they had passed through that
		valley long before this event.
		Abraham used to go to Makkah every now and then to see his wife and son. The number of these
		journeys is still unknown, but authentic historical resources spoke of four ones.
		Allâh, the Sublime, stated in the Noble Qur’ân that He had Abraham see, in his dream, that he
		slaughtered his son Ishmael, and therefore Abraham stood up to fulfill His Order:
		• “Then, when they had both submitted themselves (to the Will of Allâh), and he had laid him
		prostrate on his forehead (or on the side of his forehead for slaughtering); and We called out
		to him: “O Abraham! You have fulfilled the dream (vision)!” Verily! Thus do we reward the
		Muhsinûn (good-doers, who perform good deeds totally for Allâh’s sake only, without any
		show off or to gain praise or fame, etc. and do them in accordance to Allâh’s Orders). Verily,
		that indeed was a manifest trial — and We ransomed him with a great sacrifice (i.e. a ram)”
		[37:103-107] 
		It is mentioned in the Genesis that Ishmael was thirteen years older than his brother Ishaq. The
		sequence of the story of the sacrifice of Ishmael shows that it really happened before Ishaq’s birth,
		and that Allâh’s Promise to give Abraham another son, Ishaq, came after narration of the whole
		story.
		This story spoke of one journey – at least – before Ishmael became a young man. Al-Bukhari, on
		the authority of Ibn ‘Abbas, reported the other three journeys; a summary of which goes as follows:
		When Ishmael became a young man, he learned Arabic at the hand of the tribe of Jurhum, who
		loved him with great admiration and gave him one of their women as a wife, soon after his mother
		died. Having wanted to see his wife and son again, Abraham came to Makkah, Ishmael’s marriage,
		but he didn’t find him at home. He asked Ishmael’s wife about her husband and how they were
		doing. She complained of poverty, so he asked her to tell Ishmael to change his doorstep. Ishmael
		understood the message, divorced his wife and got married to the daughter of Mudad bin ‘Amr, chief
		of the tribe of Jurhum.
		Once more, Abraham came to see his son, but again didn’t find him at home. He asked his new wife
		the same previous question, to which she thanked Allâh. Abraham asked her to tell Ishmael to keep
		his doorstep (i.e. to keep her as wife) and went back to Palestine.
		A third time, Abraham came to Makkah to find Ishmael sharpening an arrow under a lofty tree near
		Zamzam. The meeting, after a very long journey of separation, was very touching for a father so
		affectionate and a so dutiful and righteous son. This time, father and son built Al-Ka‘bah and raised
		its pillars, and Abraham, in compliance with Allâh’s Commandment, called unto people to make
		pilgrimage to it.
		By the grace of Allâh, Ishmael had twelve sons from the daughter of Mudad, whose names were
		Nabet, Qidar, Edbael, Mebsham, Mishma’, Duma, Micha, Hudud, Yetma, Yetour, Nafis and Qidman,
		and who ultimately formed twelve tribes inhabiting Makkah and trading between Yemen,
		geographical Syria and Egypt. Later on, these tribes spread all over, and even outside, the
		peninsula. All their tidings went into oblivion except for the descendants of Nabet and Qidar.
		The Nabeteans – sons of Nabet – established a flourishing civilization in the north of Hijaz, they
		instituted a powerful government which spread out its domain over all neighbouring tribes, and
		made Petra their capital. Nobody dared challenge their authority until the Romans came and
		managed to eliminate their kingdom. After extensive research and painstaking investigation, Mr.
		Sulaiman An-Nadwi came to the conclusion that the Ghassanide kings, along with the Aws and
		Khazraj were not likely to be Qahtanians but rather Nabeteans.
		Descendants of Qidar, the son of Ishmael, lived long in Makkah increasing in number, of them
		issued ‘Adnan and son Ma‘ad, to whom ‘Adnanian Arabs traced back their ancestry. ‘Adnan is the
		twenty-first grandfather in the series of the Prophetic ancestry. It was said that whenever Prophet
		Muhammad Õáì Çááå Úáíå æÓáã spoke of his ancestry he would stop at ‘Adnan and say:
		“Genealogists tell lies” and did not go farther than him. A group of scholars, however, favoured the
		probability of going beyond ‘Adnan attaching no significance to the aforementioned Prophetic Hadith.
		They went on to say that there were exactly forty fathers between ‘Adnan and Abraham (Peace be
		upon them).
		Nizar, Ma‘ad’s only son , had four sons who branched out into four great tribes; Eyad, Anmar, Rabi‘a
		and Mudar. These last two sub-branched into several septs. Rabi‘a fathered Asad, ‘Anazah, ‘Abdul
		Qais, and Wa’il’s two sons (Bakr and Taghlib), Hanifa and many others.
		Mudar tribes branched out into two great divisions: Qais ‘Ailan bin Mudar and septs of Elias bin
		Mudar. Of Qais ‘Ailan were the Banu Saleem, Banu Hawazin, and Banu Ghatafan of whom descended
		‘Abs, Zubyan, Ashja‘ and Ghani bin A‘sur. Of Elias bin Mudar were Tamim bin Murra, Hudhail bin
		Mudrika, Banu Asad bin Khuzaimah and septs of Kinana bin Khuzaimah, of whom came Quraish, the
		descendants of Fahr bin Malik bin An-Nadr bin Kinana.
		Quraish branched out into various tribes, the most famous of whom were Jumah, Sahm, ‘Adi,
		Makhzum, Tayim, Zahra and the three septs of Qusai bin Kilab: ‘Abdud-Dar bin Qusai, Asad bin
		‘Abdul ‘Uzza bin Qusai and ‘Abd Manaf bin Qusai.
		‘Abd Manaf branched out into four tribes: ‘Abd Shams, Nawfal, Muttalib and Hashim. It is, however,
		from the family of Hashim that Allâh selected Prophet Muhammad bin ‘Abdullah bin ‘Abdul-Muttalib
		bin Hashim (Peace be upon him).
		Prophet Muhammad (Peace be upon him) said:
		• “Allâh selected Ishmael from the sons of Abraham, Kinana from the sons of Ishmael,
		Quraish from the sons of Kinana, Hashim from the sons of Quraish and He selected me from
		the sons of Hashim.”
		Al-‘Abbas bin ‘Abdul-Muttalib quoted the Messenger of Allâh (Peace be upon him) as saying: 
		• “Allâh created mankind and chose me from the best whereof, He chose the tribes and
		selected me from the best whereof; and He chose families and selected me from the best
		whereof. I am the very best in person and family.”
		Having increased in number, children of ‘Adnan, in pursuit of pastures and water, spread out over
		various parts of Arabia.
		The tribe of ‘Abdul Qais, together with some septs of Bakr bin Wa’il and Tamim, emigrated to
		Bahrain where they dwelt.
		Banu Hanifa bin Sa‘b bin Ali bin Bakr went to settle in Hijr, the capital of Yamama. All the tribes of
		Bakr bin Wa’il lived in an area of land which included Yamama, Bahrain, Saif Kazima, the sea shore,
		the outer borders of Iraq, Ablah and Hait.
		Most of the tribe of Taghlib lived in the Euphrates area while some of them lived with Bakr.
		Banu Tamim lived in Basra semi-desert.
		Banu Saleem lived in the vicinity of Madinah on the land stretching from Wadi Al-Qura to Khaibar
		onwards to the eastern mountains to Harrah.
		Thaqif dwelt in Ta’if and Hawazin east of Makkah near Autas on the road from Makkah to Basra.
		Banu Asad lived on the land east of Taimâ’ and west of Kufa, while family of Tai’ lived between Banu
		Asad and Taimâ’. They were five-day-walk far from Kufa.
		Zubyan inhabited the plot of and between Taimâ’ and Hawran.
		Some septs of Kinana lived in Tihama, while septs of Quraish dwelt in Makkah and its suburbs.
		Quraish remained completely disunited until Qusai bin Kilab managed to rally their ranks on
		honourable terms attaching major prominence to their status and importance.
	</item>
</string-array>



<string-array name="chapter_2">

	<item>Rulership in Yemen</item> 
	<item>Rulership in Heerah</item> 
	<item>Rulership in Geographical Syria</item> 
	<item>Rulership in Hijaz</item> 
	<item>The Reasons of this war have been illustrated in three versions</item> 
	<item>Rulership in Pan-Arabia</item> 
	<item>The political situation</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_2_content">
	<item>
		When talking about the Arabs before Islam,we deem it necessary to draw a mini-picture of the
		history of rulership, princeship, sectarianism and the religious dominations of the Arabs, so as to
		facilitate the understanding of emergent circumstances when Islam appeared.
		When the sun of Islam rose, rulers of Arabia were of two kinds: crowned kings, who were in fact not
		independent; and heads of tribes and clans, who enjoyed the same authorities and privileges
		possessed by crowned kings and were mostly independent, though some of whom could have shown
		some kind of submission to a crowned king. The crowned kings were only those of Yemen, Heerah
		and Ghassan. All other rulers of Arabia were non-crowned. 
	</item>
	<item>
		The folks of Sheba were one of the oldest nations of the pure Arabs, who lived in Yemen.
		Excavations at “Or” brought to light their existence twenty five centuries B.C. Their civilization
		flourished, and their domain spread eleven centuries B.C.
		It is possible to divide their ages according to the following estimation:
		1. The centuries before 650 B.C., during which their kings were called “Makrib Sheba”. Their
		capital was “Sarwah”, also known as “Khriba”, whose ruins lie in a spot, a day’s walk from
		the western side of “Ma’rib”. During this period, they started building the “Dam of Ma’rib”
		which had great importance in the history of Yemen. Sheba was also said to have had so
		great a domain that they had colonies inside and outside Arabia.
		2. From 650 B.C. until 115 B.C. During this era, they gave up the name “Makrib” and assumed
		the designation of “Kings of Sheba”. They also made Ma’rib their capital instead of Sarwah.
		The ruins of Ma’rib lie at a distance of sixty miles east of San‘a.
		3. From 115 B.C. until 300 A.D. During this period, the tribe of Himyar conquered the kingdom
		of Sheba and took Redan for capital instead of Ma’rib. Later on, Redan was called “Zifar”. Its
		ruins still lie on Mudawwar Mountain near the town of “Yarim”. During this period, they
		began to decline and fall. Their trade failed to a very great extent, firstly, because of the
		Nabetean domain over the north of Hijaz; secondly, because of the Roman superiority over
		the naval trade routes after the Roman conquest of Egypt, Syria and the north of Hijaz; and
		thirdly, because of the inter-tribal warfare. Thanks to the three above-mentioned factors,
		families of Qahtan were disunited and scatteredout.
		4. From 300 A.D. until Islam dawned on Yemen. This period witnessed a lot of disorder and
		turmoil. The great many and civil wars rendered the people of Yemen liable to foreign
		subjection and hence loss of independence. During this era, the Romans conquered ‘Adn and
		even helped the Abyssinians (Ethiopians) to occupy Yemen for the first time in 340 A.D.,
		making use of the constant intra-tribal conflict of Hamdan and Himyar. The Abyssinian
		(Ethiopian) occupation of Yemen lasted until 378 A.D., whereafter Yemen regained its
		independence. Later on, cracks began to show in Ma’rib Dam which led to the Great Flood
		(450 or 451 A.D.) mentioned in the Noble Qur’ân. This was a great event which caused the
		fall of the entire Yemeni civilization and the dispersal of the nations living therein.
		In 523, Dhu Nawas, a Jew, despatched a great campaign against the Christians of Najran in order to
		force them to convert into Judaism. Having refused to do so, they were thrown alive into a big ditch
		where a great fire had been set. The Qur’ân referred to this event:
		• “Cursed were the people of the ditch.” [85:4]
		This aroused great wrath among the Christians, and especially the Roman emperors, who not only
		instigated the Abyssinians (Ethiopians) against Arabs but also assembled a large fleet which helped
		the Abyssinian (Ethiopian) army, of seventy thousand warriors, to effect a second conquest of
		Yemen in 525 A.D., under the leadership of Eriat, who was granted rulership over Yemen, a position
		he held until he was assassinated by one of his army leaders, Abraha, who, after reconciliation with
		the king of Abyssinia, took rulership over Yemen and, later on, deployed his soldiers to demolish AlKa‘bah,
		and , hence, he and his soldiers came to be known as the “Men of the Elephant”. 
		After the “Elephant” incident, the people of Yemen, under the leadership of Ma‘dikarib bin Saif Dhu
		Yazin Al-Himyari, and through Persian assistance, revolted against the Abyssinian (Ethiopian)
		invaders, restored independence and appointed Ma‘dikarib as their king. However, Ma‘dikarib was
		assassinated by an Abyssinian (Ethiopian) he used to have him around for service and protection.
		The family of Dhu Yazin was thus deprived of royalty forever. Kisra, the Persian king, appointed a
		Persian ruler over San‘a and thus made Yeme n a Persian colony. Persian rulers maintained rulership
		of Yemen until Badhan, the last of them, embraced Islam in 638 A.D., thus terminating the Persian
		domain over Yemen. 
	</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_2_content">
	
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_2_content">

	<item>

	</item> 

</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_2_content">

	<item>

	</item> 

</string-array>




<string-array name="chapter_3">

	<item>The Religious situation</item> 

</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_4">
	<item>Social life of the Arabs</item> 
	<item>The Economic Situation</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_5">
	<item>The prophetic Family</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_6">

	<item>His Birth</item> 
	<item>Babyhood</item> 
	<item>Back to his passionate Mother</item> 
	<item>To His compassionate Grandfather</item> 
	<item>Bahira, the Monk</item> 
	<item>The Sacrilegious wars</item> 
	<item>Al-Fudoul confederacy</item> 
	<item>Muhammad’s Early Job</item> 
	<item>His Marriage to Khadijah</item> 
	<item>Rebuilding Al-Ka‘bah and the Arbitration Issue</item> 
	<item>A Rapid Review of Muhammad’s Biography before commissioning of the Prophethood</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_7">
	<item>In the Cave of Hira’</item> 
	<item>Gabriel brings down the Revelation</item> 
	<item>Interruption of Revelation</item> 
	<item>Once more, Gabriel brings Allah’s Revelation</item> 
	<item>Some details pertinent to the successive stages of Revelation</item> 
	<item>Proclaiming Allah, the All-High; and the Immediate Constituents</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_8">
	<item> Strife in the Way of the Call  </item> 
	<item>Three years of Secret Call</item> 
	<item>The Early Converts</item> 
	<item>As-Salat (the Prayer)</item> 
	<item>The Quraishites learn about the Call</item>  
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_9">
	<item>Open Preaching</item> 
	<item>First Revelation regarding the Preaching</item> 
	<item>Calling the Closest Kinspeople</item> 
	<item>On Mount As-Safa</item> 
	<item>Shouting the Truth and the Polytheists’ Reaction</item> 
	<item>An Advisory Council to debar</item> 
	<item>Pilgrims from Muhammad’s Call</item> 
	<item>Attempts made to check the Onward March of Islam</item> 
	<item>Persecutions</item> 
	<item>The House of Al-Arqum</item> 
	<item>The First Migration to Abyssinia (Ethiopia)</item> 
	<item>Quraish’s Machination against the Emigrants</item> 
	<item>Once more Quraish approaches Abu Talib</item> 
	<item>The Tyrants’ Decision to kill the Prophet (Peace be upon him)</item> 
	<item>The Conversion of Hamzah bin ‘Abdul-Muttalib</item> 
	<item>The Conversion of ‘Umar bin Al-Khattab</item> 
	<item>Quraish’s Representative negotiates with the Messenger of Allah (Peace be upon him)</item> 
	<item>Abu Talib assmbles Bani Hashim and Bani Al-Muttalib</item> 
	<item>General Social Boycott</item> 
	<item>A Pact of Injustice and Aggression</item> 
	<item>The Final Phase of the Diplomacy of Negotiation</item> 
	<item>The Year of Grief</item> 
	<item>Abu Talib’s Death</item> 
	<item>Khadijah passes away to the Mercy of Allah</item> 
	<item>His Marriage to Sawdah (May be please with her) in Shawwal, the tenth year of Prophethood</item> 
	<item>Factors inspiring patience and perserverance</item> 

</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_10">
	<item>Calling unto Islam beyond Makkah</item>
	<item>Islam being introduced to Arabian Tribes and Individuals</item> 
	<item>Hope inspiring Breezes from the Madinese</item> 
	<item>Marriage of the Prophet (Peace be upon him) to Aisha (May Allah be please with her)</item> 
	<item>Al-Isra’ and Al-Mir‘raj</item> 
	<item>The First ‘Aqabah Pledge</item> 
	<item>The Muslim Envoy in Madinah</item> 
	<item>The Second ‘Aqabah Pledge</item> 
	<item>The Vanguard of Migration (in the Cause of Allah)</item> 
	<item>In An-Nadwah (Council) House</item> 
	<item>The Parliament of Quraish</item> 
	<item>Migration of the Prophet (Peace be upon him)</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_11">

	<item>The Status Quo in Madinah at the Time of Emigration</item> 
	<item>A New Society being built</item> 
	<item>A Charter of Islamic Alliance</item> 
	<item>A Cooperation and Non-Aggression</item> 
	<item>Pact with the Jews</item> 
	<item>The Prophet on the Battlefield</item> 
	<item>Pre-Badr Missions and Invasions</item> 
	<item>The Battle of Badr - The First Decisive Battle in the History of Islam</item> 
	<item>Reason of the Battle</item> 
	<item>Some Significant Instances of Devotion</item> 
	<item>Reaction in Makkah</item> 
	<item>Madinah receives the News of Victory</item> 
	<item>The Battle of Badr in its Qur’anic Context</item> 
	<item>The Military Activities between Badr and Uhud</item> 
	<item>Al-Kudr Invasion</item> 
	<item>An Attempt on the Life of the Prophet (Peace be upon him)</item> 
	<item>Invasion of Bani Qainuqa‘</item> 
	<item>The Qainuqa‘ Jews breach the Covenant</item> 
	<item>As-Sawiq Invasion</item> 
	<item>Dhi Amr Invasion</item> 
	<item>Ka‘b bin Al-Ashraf, killed</item> 
	<item>4</item> 
	<item>The Invasion of Buhran</item> 
	<item>Zaid bin Harithah leads a Compaign on the Trade Routes of Quraish</item> 
	<item>The Battle of Uhud</item> 
	<item>A Consultation Assembly for a Defence Plan</item> 
	<item>Dividing the Islamic Army into phalanxes and Departure to the Battlefield</item> 
	<item>Parading the Army</item> 
	<item>Passing the Night between Uhud and Madinah</item> 
	<item>The Rebellion of ‘Abdullah bin Ubai and his Followers</item> 
	<item>The Remainder of the Islamic Army are on the Move to Uhud</item> 
	<item>The Defence Plan</item> 
	<item>The Messenger of Allah (Peace b e upon him) implants the Spirit of Bravery among his Armed Forces</item> 
	<item>Recruitment of the Makkan Army</item> 
	<item>Political Manoeuvres of Quraish</item> 
	<item>The effort of Quraishite women at waging the Zeal of Men</item> 
	<item>The Combat</item> 
	<item>Assassination of Asadullah (the Lion of Allah) Hamzah bin ‘Abdul Muttalib</item> 
	<item>Bringing the Situation under Control</item> 
	<item>From his wife’s lap to Sword-fights and Sorrows</item> 
	<item>The Contribution of the Archers squad to the Battle.</item> 
	<item>The Archers’s Fatal Mistake</item> 
	<item>The Most Awkward Hour in the Messenger’s Life</item> 
	<item>Multilation of the Martyrs</item> 
	<item>Burial of the Martyrs</item> 
	<item>Hamrâ’ Al-Asad Invasion</item> 
	<item>The Observations of the Noble Qur’ân on the Battle of Uhud</item> 
	<item>Lessons and Moralities</item> 
	<item>Military Platoons and Missions between the Battle of Uhud and the Battle of the</item> 
	<item>Confederates</item> 
	<item>Abi Salamah Mission</item> 
	<item>An Errand led by ‘Abdullah bin Unais</item> 
	<item>The Event of Ar-Raji‘</item> 
	<item>The Tragedy of Ma‘una Well</item> 
	<item>Bani An-Nadeer Invasion</item> 
	<item>The Invasion of Najd</item> 
	<item>The Invasion of Badr, the Second</item> 
	<item>The Invasion of Doumat Al-Jaudal</item> 
	<item>Al-Ahzab (the Confederates) Invasion</item> 
	<item>Invading Banu Quraiza</item> 
	<item>Military Activities continued</item> 
	<item>Bani Lihyan Invasion</item> 
	<item>Expeditions and Delegations continued</item> 
	<item>Bani Al-Mustaliq (Muraisi‘) Ghazwah Sha‘ban 6 Hijri</item> 
	<item>The treacherous Role of the Hypocrites</item> 
	<item>Prior to the Bani Al-Mustaliq Ghazwah</item> 
	<item>The wicked Role they played in the Course of the Ghazwah of Bani Al-Mustaliq</item> 
	<item>The Slander Affair</item> 
	<item>Delegations and Expeditions following</item> 
	<item>Al-Muraisi‘ Ghazwah</item> 
	<item>Al-Hudaibiyah Treaty (Dhul Qu‘dah 6 A.H.)</item> 
	<item>Al-Hudaibiya Treaty: Socio Political Impact</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_12">
	<item>A New Phase of Islamic Action</item> 
	<item>The Prophet’s Plans to spread the Message of Islam to beyond Arabia</item> 
	<item>A Deputation to Abyssinia (Ethiopia)</item> 
	<item>Letter to the Vicegerent of Egypt, called Muqawqas</item> 
	<item>A Letter to chosroes, Emperor of Persia</item> 
	<item>The Envoy to Caesar, King of Rome</item> 
	<item>5</item> 
	<item>A Letter to Mundhir bin Sawa, Governor of Bahrain</item> 
	<item>A Letter to Haudha bin ‘Ali, Governor of Yamama</item> 
	<item>A Letter to Harith bin Abi Shamir Al-Ghassani, King of Damascus</item> 
	<item>A Letter to the King of ‘Oman, Jaifer, and his Bother ‘Abd Al-Jalandi</item> 
	<item>Post-Hudaibiyah Hostilities</item> 
	<item>Dhu Qarad Invasion</item> 
	<item>The Conquest of Khaibar (in Moharram, 7 A.H.)</item> 
	<item>The Actual operation begins</item> 
	<item>The Second Part of Khaibar Conquered</item> 
	<item>Negotiations</item> 
	<item>Distribution of Spoils</item> 
	<item>Sporadic Invasions</item> 
	<item>The Expedition called Dhat-ur-Riqa‘ (in the year 7 A.H.)</item> 
	<item>The Compensatory ‘Umrah (Lesser Pilgrimage)</item> 
	<item>The Battle of Mu’tah</item> 
	<item>Dhat As-Salasil Compaign</item> 
	<item>Khadrah Campaign</item> 
	<item>The Conquest of Makkah</item> 
	<item>Pre-conquest Events</item> 
	<item>Preparations for the Attach on Makkah, and the Prophet’s Attempt at imposing a News Black-out</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_13">
	<item>Hunain Ghazwah</item> 
	<item>The Enemy’s march and their Encampment at Awtas</item> 
	<item>The war-experienced Man wongs the Leader’s Judgement</item> 
	<item>Reconnoitering the Weapons of the Messenger of Allah(Peace be upon him)</item> 
	<item>Reconnoitering the Enemy’s Weapons</item> 
	<item>The Messenger of Allah (peace be upon him) leaves Makkah for Hunain</item> 
	<item>The Islamic Army stunned the Archers and the Attackers</item> 
	<item>Muslims’ return to the Battlefield, and the fierceness of the Fight</item> 
	<item>Reverse of Fortunes and the Enemy’s utter Defeat</item> 
	<item>Hot pursuit of the Enemy</item> 
	<item>Ta’if Compaign</item> 
	<item>The Distribution of the Booty at al-Ji‘ranah</item> 
	<item>The Helpers (Al-Ansar) are furious at the Messenger of Allah (Peace be upon him)</item> 
	<item>Arrival of the Hawazin Delegation</item> 
	<item>Lesser Pilgrimage (Al-‘Umrah) to Makkah and leaving for Madinah</item> 
	<item>Missions and Platoons After the Conquest</item> 
	<item>The Platoons</item> 
</string-array>
<string-array name="chapter_14">
	<item>The underlying Reasons</item> 
	<item>General News about the Byzantines and Ghassanide Preparations for War</item> 
	<item>Particular News about the Byzantine and Ghassanide preparations for War</item> 
	<item>The Muslim Army is leaving for Tabuk</item> 
	<item>The Army of Islam at Tabuk</item> 
	<item>Returning to Madinah</item> 
	<item>The People Who lagged Behind</item> 
	<item>The Invasion of Tabuk and its Far-Reaching Ramifications</item> 
	<item>The Qur’ânic Verses Relating to this Invasion</item> 

</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_15">
	<item>Abu Bakr performs the Pilgrimage</item> 
	<item>A Meditation on the Ghazawat</item> 

</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_17">
	<item>The Delegations</item> 
	<item>The Success and Impact of the Call</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_18">
	<item>The Last Expeditions</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_19">
	<item>Symptoms of Farewell</item> 
	<item>The Start of the Disease</item> 
	<item>The Last Week</item> 
	<item>Five days before death</item> 
	<item>Four days before his death</item> 
	<item>A Day or Two prior to Death</item> 
	<item>A Day before his Death</item> 
	<item>The Last day Alive</item> 
	<item>The Prophet (Peace be upon him) breathes his Last</item> 
	<item>The companions’ concern over the Prophet’s Death</item> 
	<item>Umar’s Attitude</item> 
	<item>Abu Bakr’s Attitude</item> 
	<item>Burial and Farewell Preparations to his Honourable Body</item> 
</string-array>

<string-array name="chapter_18">
	<item>Beauty of creation</item> 
	<item>The perfection of Soul and Nobility</item>
</string-array>


<string-array name="chapters"> 
	<item>Location and nature of Arab Tribes</item>
	<item>Rulership and Princeship among the Arabs</item> 
	<item>Religions of the Arabs</item> 
	<item>Aspects of Pre-Islamic Arabian Society</item> 
	<item>The Lineage and Family of Muhammad (Peace be upon him)</item> 
	<item>Muhammad’s Birth and Forty years prior Prophethood</item> 
	<item>In the Shade of the Message and Prophethood</item> 
	<item>Phases and stages of the call : The First Stage</item>
	<item>Phases and stages of the call : The Second Phase</item>
	<item>Phases and stages of the call : The Third Phase</item>
	<item>Life in Madinah: The First Phase </item>
	<item>Life in Madinah: The Second Phase </item>
	<item>Life in Madinah: The Third Phase </item>

	<item>The Invasion of Tabuk in Rajab, in the year 9 A.H.</item> 
	<item>Some Important Events that featured that Year</item>
	<item>People embrace the Religion of Allah in Large Crowds</item> 
	<item>The Farewell Pilgrimage</item> 
	<item>The Journey to Allah, the Sublime</item> 
	<item>The Prophetic Household, The Prophet (Peace be upon him), Attributes and Manners</item> 
</string-array>


